<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    tools:ignore="MissingTranslation">
    <string name="app_name">Zombies! Hide!</string>
    <string name="dummy_button">Dummy Button</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>
    <string name="welcome_msg">Thank you for playing \'Zombies! Hide!\'\n\nAll code written by Chris Caron\n\nTo report bugs or send feedback please send email to ccaronsoftware@gmail.com
\n\nRULES
\n\nZombies! Hide! is based on the board game Zombicide which is a cooperative board game
where one or more players face hordes of Zombies controlled by the game itself.
Each player controls one to four Survivors in a fantasy world
invaded by Zombies. The goal is simply to complete the Quest
objectives, survive, and kill as many Zombies as possible!
Zombies are slow and predictable, but there are a lot of them.
Watch out for their Abomination and Necromancer bosses, too!
Survivors use whatever they can get their hands on to kill
Zombies. The better the weapon, the higher the body count,
and the more Zombies appear, attracted by the onslaught!
Survivors can trade equipment, and players can share tactics.
Only through cooperation can you achieve the Quest objectives
and survive. Battling Zombies is fun, but you will also need
to rescue other Survivors, find food and weapons, uncover the
Necromancers’ secrets, and much more. The phases of the game are described below.
\n\nPLAYERS’ PHASE\n
On the player\'s turn they activate their Survivors one at a time, in the order of his choice.
Each Survivor can initially perform three Actions per Turn,
though Skills may allow him to perform extra Actions as the
game progresses. The Survivor uses his Actions to kill Zombies, move around the board, and performs other tasks to
accomplish the various Quest objectives. Some Actions make
noise, and noise attracts Zombies!
Once a player has activated all his Survivors, the player to
his left takes his Turn, activating his Survivors in the same
manner.
When all the players have completed their Turns, the Players’
Phase ends.
\n\nZOMBIES’ PHASE\n
All Zombies on the board activate and spend one Action either
attacking a Survivor next to them or, if they have nobody to
attack, moving toward the Survivors or noisy Zones. Some
Zombies, called Runners, get two Actions, so they can attack
twice, attack and move, move and attack, or move twice.
Once all Zombies have performed their Actions, new Zombies appear in all active Spawn Zones on the board
\n\nEND PHASE\n
At the end of the round all noise markers are reset and the next round begins.
\n\nWINNING AND LOSING\n
The game is lost when all Survivors have been eliminated or
if too many Necromancers escape. Some Missions can be lost
when certain conditions are met (losing a single Survivor, for
example).
The game is won immediately when all of the Quest objectives have been accomplished. Zombicide: Black Plague is a
cooperative game, so all players win if the Quest objectives
are fulfilled.

    </string>
    <string name="email_">An error occurred trying to send report:\n%s</string>
    <string name="p2p_name_unassigned">Unassigned</string>

    <string name="char_lock_tucker">Complete \'Big Game Hunting\' in Medium difficulty.</string>
    <string name="char_lock_jain">Complete \'The Black Book\' in Hard difficulty</string>
    <string name="char_lock_benson">Complete \'The Evil Temple\' in Hard difficulty</string>
    <string name="char_lock_wolfz">Unlock Wolfzburg</string>



    <string name="popup_button_back">Back</string>
    <string name="popup_button_send">Send</string>
    <string name="popup_button_newgame">New Game</string>
    <string name="popup_button_cancel_mp">Cancel Multi-player</string>

    <string name="popup_title_welcome">Welcome</string>
    <string name="popup_title_legend">Legend</string>
    <string name="popup_title_skills">Skills</string>
    <string name="popup_title_email">Email a report to the Author</string>
    <string name="popup_title_searchables">Searchable</string>
    <string name="popup_title_choose">Choose</string>
    <string name="popup_title_difficulty">Difficulty %s</string>
    <string name="popup_title_load_quest">Load Quest</string>
    <string name="popup_title_load_saved">Load Saved</string>
    <string name="popup_title_choose_color">Choose Color</string>
    <string name="popup_title_choose_version">Choose Version</string>
    <string name="popup_title_choose_quest">Choose Quest</string>
    <string name="popup_title_wolflocked">Wolfburg Locked</string>
    <string name="popup_title_quest">Quest %1$d : %2$s</string>
    <string name="popup_title_choose_players">Choose Players</string>
    <string name="popup_title_assign">Assign</string>

    <string name="popup_message_sending_report">Sending report</string>
    <string name="popup_message_confirm_restart">Are you sure you want to start a new game?</string>
    <string name="popup_message_confirm_disconnect">Are you sure you want to Disconnect?</string>
    <string name="popup_message_unlock_wolfburg">Finish last level of Black Plague at Medium difficulty to unlock</string>
    <string name="popup_message_err_fileopen">Failed to open %s</string>
    <string name="popup_message_err_nonemptyname">Please set non empty name for display</string>

    <string name="toast_msg_minplayers">Must have at least one player</string>
    <string name="toast_msg_maxplayers">Can only have %d players at a time</string>
    <string name="dpad_lh">LH</string>
    <string name="dpad_rh">RH</string>
    <string name="dpad_zm">ZM</string>

    <string-array name="popup_message_choose_game_types">
        <item>LEVEL</item>
        <item>SAVED</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="popup_message_choose_game_version_debug">
        <item>Black Plague</item>
        <item>Wolfsburg</item>
        <item>All (DEBUG)</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="popup_message_choose_game_version">
        <item>Black Plague</item>
        <item>Wolfsburg</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="label_empty">-- Empty --</string>
    <string name="popup_title_organize">ORGANIZE</string>
    <string name="label_left_hand">Left Hand</string>
    <string name="label_right_hand">Right Hand</string>
    <string name="label_body">Body</string>
    <string name="label_backpack">Backpack</string>

</resources>